Guide to the Lynn Riggs Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1924-54; Series II; 7.25; (17 boxes)
  - NOVELS
    - The Affair at Easter
      - Part IV, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, 1954 Mar-Apr (Box 10, Folder 183)
      - Part V, draft, typescript carbon, corrected (includes pages of Part I), 1953 Apr (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - The Cream in the Well
      - Notes, holograph and typescript, 1928 Feb 2 (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Untitled
      - "Notes for a Novel," holograph, 1941 Dec 21 (Box 10, Folder 186)
  - PLAYS
    - All the Way Home
      - Draft 1, typescript carbon, corrected (noted as "2nd Draft") (Box 10, Folder 187)
      - Draft 2, typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 188)
      - Draft 2, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 189)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 190)
      - Draft 4, typescript and carbon, corrected (noted as "2nd draft"), 1947 Mar (Box 10, Folder 191)
      - Draft 5, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 192)
      - Draft 5, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 193)
      - Dialog notes, typescript, corrected, 1946 Nov 21 (Box 11, Folder 194)
      - Draft 6, typescript carbon, corrected (with "Memorandum of Miss Helburn's lunch with Lynn Riggs re: Verdigris Primitive ", 1947 May 21), 1947 Aug (Box 11, Folder 195)
      - Notes, typescript, 1948 Aug 20 (Box 11, Folder 196)
      - Draft 7, typescript, 1948 Oct 25 (Box 11, Folder 197)
      - Draft 7, retyped copy, typescript carbon (noted as "final draft"), 1948 Oct 25 (Box 11, Folder 198)
    - Borned in Texas [Roadside]
      - Printed version (published as Roadside ), corrected, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 199)
      - Synopses for screenplay of Roadside, 1930 Oct 2 (Box 11, Folder 200)
      - Production notebook, ca. 1940s (Box 11, Folder 201)
      - Notes, 1945-46 (Box 12, Folder 202)
      - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 203)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 204)
      - "Birth speech" typescript carbon, corrected (with notes), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 205)
      - "Tall Tale, a Song for 'Borned in Texas'," typescript and holograph, 1950 Aug 16 (Box 12, Folder 206)
      - Production blueprints for Festival Theatre Production
        See: Oversize, Box 32, folder 543
    - College Play
      - Synopsis, typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - The Cow in the Trailer (co-written by Ramon Naya)
      - Draft 1 notes and fragments, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 208)
      - Draft 1, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 209)
      - Draft 2, typescript carbon, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 210)
      - Working notebook, 1938-39 (Box 12, Folder 211)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1937 (Box 12, Folder 212)
      - Draft 4, typescript carbon, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - The Cream in the Well
      - Working notebook, 1939-40 (Box 12, Folder 214)
      - Draft 1, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 215)
      - Draft 2, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 216)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon, corrected, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 217)
    - Dance of Desire
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 218)
    - Days Together
      - Notes (including biographical notes about Lynn Riggs), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 219)
    - Education for The Chart of Plenty
      - Draft, typescript carbon with notes, 1938 Jun 6 (Box 13, Folder 220)
    - Encounter in Guerrero
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - Friendly Persuasion
      - Notes, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 222)
    - Friends and Countrymen
      - Notes, holograph and typescript, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 223)
    - The Gay Nineties
      Benefit for Soldiers Service Club written with William Saroyan)
      - Script, typescript and carbon corrected, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 224)
    - God Save the Prince (by Duncan Lee, pseud.)
      - Synopsis, typescript carbon, corrected, with notes, 1934 Jan 28 (Box 13, Folder 225)
      - Working notebook, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 226)
      - Draft pages, Prologue and Act I, typescript carbon (Box 13, Folder 227)
    - Green Grow the Lilacs
      - Notes (with lyrics and flyer for Oklahoma! ), 1930 (Box 13, Folder 228)
      - Artwork (watercolor sketches) by Sidney Lumet for School of Performing Arts production, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 229)
    - Hang on to Love [Domino Parlor]
      - Version 1 draft, typescript carbon, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 230)
      - Version 2 draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 231)
    - The High Mountain
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 232)
    - The Hunger I Got [Sidetracked]
      - Working notebook, 1938-39 (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - Knives from Syria
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 234)
    - A Lantern T' See By
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 235)
    - A Lasting Spring
      - Notes, 1941 Dec 27 (Box 14, Folder 236)
    - Laughter From a Cloud
      - Draft 1, typescript, 1946 Feb 15 (Box 14, Folder 237)
      - Draft 1, typescript carbon, corrected, 1946 Feb 15 (Box 14, Folder 238)
      - Draft 1 "revised", typescript carbon, corrected, 1946 Feb 15 (Box 14, Folder 239)
      - Draft 2, typescript carbon, corrected, 1946 May 3 (Box 14, Folder 240)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon (noted as "first draft, #3"), 1947 (Box 14, Folder 241)
      - Draft 4, typescript carbon, 1947 Jun 14 (Box 14, Folder 242)
      - Draft 4, typescript carbon, corrected, 1947 Jun 14 (Box 14, Folder 243)
      - Draft 5, typescript (with photograph print of stage set), 1947 Oct 25 (Box 15, Folder 244)
      - Reading announcement, 1948 Apr 23 (Box 15, Folder 245)
    - Maria Concepción
      - Notes, 1952 Apr (Box 15, Folder 246)
      - Drafts of "Tentative structure and material of scenes", 1952 Apr-May (Box 15, Folder 247)
    - More Sky
      - Draft, typescript carbon, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 248)
    - Myth
      - Draft 1, typescript, corrected, ca. 1947 (Box 15, Folder 249)
      - Draft 2, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1947 (Box 15, Folder 250)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1947 (Box 15, Folder 251)
      - Draft 4 fragment, typescript, ca. 1947 (Box 15, Folder 252)
      - Fragment, typescript, 1948 May 16 (Box 15, Folder 253)
    - Origin: Oedipus
      - Notes, 1947 May 19 (Box 15, Folder 254)
      - Synopsis draft 1, typescript, corrected, [1947] (Box 15, Folder 255)
      - Synopsis draft 2, typescript carbon, corrected, [1947] (Box 15, Folder 256)
    - Out of Dust
      - Working notebook, 1947-49 (Box 15, Folder 257-258)
      - Notes, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 259)
      - Draft 1, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 260)
      - Draft 2, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 261)
      - Draft 2, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 262)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 263)
      - Draft 4, typescript carbon, corrected, 1949 Mar 24 (Box 16, Folder 264)
      - Casting suggestions with notes, 1949 May 18 (Box 16, Folder 265)
      - Production script and notes for Westport Country Playhouse production (with program and music for "Tulsey Town"), 1949 Aug (Box 16, Folder 266)
      - Notes on revisions, 1949 Sep (Box 16, Folder 267)
      - Draft fragments, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 268)
      - Synopsis for screenplay by Horton Foote, ca. 1949 (Box 16, Folder 269)
      - Draft 5, typescript, corrected, 1950 Feb 15 (Box 16, Folder 270)
      - Draft 6, typescript carbon, corrected, 1950 Mar 10 (Box 16, Folder 271)
      - Draft 7, typescript, 1950 Mar 10 (Box 16, Folder 272)
      - Draft 7, typescript carbon, 1950 Mar 10 (Box 16, Folder 273)
      - Draft 7, retyped copies, typescript and carbon, 1950 Mar 10 (Box 17, Folder 274)
    - The Playing Fields of America [monologue]
      - Drafts, typescript carbon, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 275)
    - Russet Mantle
      - Notes for screen adaptation, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 276)
    - Someone to Remember
      - Notes, 1953 Sep-Oct (Box 17, Folder 277)
      - Draft 1 fragments and notes (Box 17, Folder 278)
      - Draft 2, Act I, typescript carbon, 1953 Oct 25 (Box 17, Folder 279)
      - Draft 3, Act I, Scene I, typescript, corrected, 1953 Oct 23 (Box 17, Folder 280)
      - Draft 4, typescript carbon, corrected, [1953] (Box 17, Folder 281)
      - Draft 5, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 282)
      - Draft 6, Acts II and III typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 17, Folder 283)
      - Draft 7, typescript carbon, 1953 Oct 26 (Box 17, Folder 284)
      - Draft 8, typescript carbon, corrected, 1953 Oct 26 (Box 17, Folder 285)
      - Draft 9, typescript, corrected, [1953] (Box 17, Folder 286)
      - Draft 9, typescript carbon, corrected, [1953] (Box 17, Folder 287)
      - Draft 10, typescript carbon, corrected, [1953] Dec 1 (Box 18, Folder 288)
      - Draft 11, typescript (noted as "second draft"), [1953] (Box 18, Folder 289)
      - Draft 12, typescript and carbon, corrected (with notes and fragments), 1954 Feb 28 (Box 18, Folder 290)
      - Draft 13, typescript carbon, corrected, 1954 Feb 28 (Box 18, Folder 291)
    - Some Sweet Day
      - Working notebook, 1939-51 (Box 18, Folder 292)
      - Synopsis of Act II, typescript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 293)
      - "Second draft," typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 18, Folder 294)
      - Draft 3, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 295)
      - Draft 4, Act I, typescript carbon, corrected, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 296)
      - Draft 5, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 297)
      - Draft 6, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 298)
      - Draft 7, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 299)
      - Draft 8, typescript carbon, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 300)
      - Draft 8, retyped copy, typescript carbon (noted as "last version"), 1954 (Box 19, Folder 301)
      - Notes, 1952-54 (Box 19, Folder 302)
      - Set sketch, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 303)
    - Song in the A.M. [adapted from Some Sweet Day ]
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 304)
      - "Revised" draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 305)
    - Toward the Western Sky
      - Dedication, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 306)
    - Tragic Ground
      - Notes, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 307)
      - Working notebook, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 308)
      - Scenario, 1945 Mar 14 (Box 19, Folder 309)
      - Draft fragments, 1945-46 (Box 19, Folder 310-314)
      - Page revisions, ca. 1945 (Box 20, Folder 315)
      - Draft 1, typescript corrected, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 316)
      - Page revisions, 1946 Jun 15 (Box 20, Folder 317)
      - Draft 2, typescript, corrected, 1946 Jun 15 (Box 20, Folder 318)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon, 1946 Jun 15 (Box 20, Folder 319)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon, corrected, 1946 Jun 15 (Box 20, Folder 320)
      - Draft 4, mimeograph, corrected, 1946 Jun 15 (Box 20, Folder 321)
      - Notes, Act II, 1946 Jul 27 (Box 20, Folder 322)
      - Conference notes, "[Agnes] DeMille, Smith, Riggs", 1946 Aug (Box 20, Folder 323)
      - Page revisions and notes, 1946 Aug (Box 20, Folder 324)
    - Tragic Rhapsody
      - Synopsis, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 325)
    - A World Elsewhere
      - Synopsis, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 326)
      - Draft 1, typescript, corrected (noted as "second working draft"), 1936 Oct (Box 20, Folder 327)
      - Working notebook, 1937 Aug-Sep (Box 20, Folder 328)
      - Draft 2, Act II, typescript, corrected (noted as "2nd draft"), 1937 Sep-Dec (Box 21, Folder 329)
      - Draft 3, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1937 Dec (Box 21, Folder 330)
      - Draft 4, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 331)
      - Draft 4, Act III, retyped copy, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 332)
      - Galley proof, corrected, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 333)
      - Working notebook for revised version, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 334)
      - Miscellaneous draft pages, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 335)
    - The Year of Pilar [The House of Pilar]
      - Draft 1, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 336)
      - Draft 2, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 337)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Notes, 1944, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 338)
      - Script pages, 1940, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 339)
  - POEMS
    - "Abstract Painting," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 340)
    - "All Hallow's Eve," drafts, holograph and typescripts, corrected
    - "Antique Evening," draft, typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "Anniversary Song," typescript, 1948 Sep 5 (Box 22, Folder 341)
    - "April," typescript, n.d.
    - "Apparition," typescript and carbon, corrected, 1946 Sep 20
    - "At a Window," typescript, corrected
    - "The Awakening," typescript and carbon
    - "Bird in the Snow," holograph, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 342)
    - "Black Wall," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "Body on the Beach," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "Bud is Bough," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - "Bud is Bough" [collection], typescript corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 343)
    - "The Captain of a Kayak," typescript and carbon (Box 22, Folder 344)
    - "Cat and the Machine Gun," typescript carbon, 1942 Oct 29
    - "The Corrosive Season," typescript and carbon
    - "Creature," typescript carbon, corrected, 1948 Jun 11
    - "The Cross," typescript, n.d.
    - "Dark Crow," printed version, Palms, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 345)
    - "Dark Song," drafts, typescripts and carbon, corrected
    - "Dictum," typescript, corrected and printed version, New Republic, 1931
    - "Don't You Come Near Me When You Are Right," holograph, n.d.
    - "Earth's Transients," typescript, n.d.
    - "Endless Legend," typescript and carbon
    - "Epitaph," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "For an Actor in Tragedy," typescript and carbon (Box 22, Folder 346)
    - "For My Friend Bill on his Birthday," typescript carbon, 1952 Apr 6
    - "Fountain," typescript and carbon
    - "Foyer in Black and White," typescript and carbon, corrected
    - "Great Summer," drafts, typescript and carbon, 1948 Jun
    - "A Hand on Mountains," typescript carbon (Box 22, Folder 347)
    - "The Harbor," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "The Harbor," printed version, The Nation, 1932 Mar 9
    - "Hour After Dawn," typescript and carbon
    - "I Knowing...," drafts, typescript and carbon, 1946 Aug 25
    - "The Impenitent," typescript and carbon
    - "Incantation Before Spring," drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon, 1952 Mar 10
    - "The Inheritors," typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - "Interim," typescript, corrected, 1947 Feb 10
    - "I Who Have Been a Soldier," typescript, n.d.
    - "Landscape," typescript and carbon, corrected, 1946 Sep 29 (Box 22, Folder 348)
    - "Lilacs at Upton," typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - "Man at Piano," typescript and carbon, corrected
    - "Man in a Balloon Over Paul & Ellie's," typescript (with limericks), 1945 Jun 24
    - "Medallion," drafts, typescript, corrected
    - "Medieval Song," drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon (Box 22, Folder 349)
    - "Mirage," typescript, n.d.
    - "New Song," typescript and carbon, corrected, 1946 Aug 24 (Box 22, Folder 350)
    - "No Field to Beckon," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "A Note in Summer," drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1951 Aug 1
    - "A Note on Communications," typescript and carbon, 1946 Aug 3
    - "A Note on Communications, Speaking Thus...," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d.
    - "Oblique Report," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1946 Aug 4 (Box 22, Folder 351)
    - "Of Those Remembered," typescript and carbon,"
    - "One Who Never Died," printed version, New York Herald Tribune, 1928 Apr 29
    - "Parting Song," typescript, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 352)
    - "Pastoral," printed version, corrected, Harper's, 1943 Jul
    - "The Perfect Tree," typescript and carbon
    - "Personal Message," typescript, n.d.
    - "Prayer in Rain," drafts holograph and typescript, corrected, 1948 Oct 11
    - "The Room," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected
    - "Siesta," typescript, corrected, 1937 May 3 (Box 22, Folder 353)
    - "Skulls Like These," typescript and carbon
    - "A Small Intense Woman from Peru," typescript and carbon, corrected
    - "Song of October 31," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "Sonnet," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "Sonnet" and "Sonnet about Billy R.," typescript
    - "Sonnet about Billy R.," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "Sonnet for Enrique," typescript, 1937 Mat 5
    - "Sonnet 1," typescript, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 354)
    - "Sonnet 2," typescript and carbon, 1952 May
    - "Sonnet 3," typescript, corrected, 1952 May 7
    - "Sonnet 4," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1952 May 9
    - "Specifically Love," holograph, n.d.
    - "Spring Rain," drafts, typescript and carbon, 1952 May 11
    - "Still Season," typescript, carbon and printed version
    - "Table Talk - Variations on Themes" and "Afterthoughts," typescript and carbon (Box 22, Folder 355)
    - "Taos Calendar," typescript carbon, 1947 Feb 7
    - "Taos Calendar #2," typescript carbon, 1947 Feb 10
    - "Telling Myself This and That," drafts, typescript and acrbon, corrected
    - "Three Men in Summer," typescript and carbon, 1952 May 28
    - "Threnody for the Slain," printed version, n.d.
    - "To a Camofleur," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected
    - "To a Camofleur," printed version, The Nation, 1943 Mar 13
    - "To a Room," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1948 Sep (Box 22, Folder 356)
    - "The War Effort of Private O'Hara," typescript, corrected, 1942 Oct 26 (Box 22, Folder 357)
    - "What Star?" (for M. H.), typescript and carbon
    - "Winter Rain," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected
    - "The Wing in Air," typescript, corrected, 1952 Jun 12
    - "Wish Me Well," holograph, n.d.
    - "Wren and Root with Us," typescript carbon
    - "The Year in Front of Us," typescript, 1946 Dec 31 (Box 22, Folder 358)
    - "Yet the Earth," draft typescript carbon, 1934 Jan 16
    - Untitled Poems, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 359)
    - Notes for poems, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 360)
  - REVIEWS
    - "High, Wide, and Handsome," review of Singing Cowboy: A Book of Western Songs, printed version, The Nation (Box 22, Folder 361)
    - Review of That Bright Heat by George O'Neil, printed version, Daily Oklahoman, 1928 Mar 25 (Box 22, Folder 362)
  - SCREENPLAYS
    - Andrew's Harvest
      - Screen treatment, mimeograph, 1934 Apr 2 (Box 22, Folder 363)
    - A Day in Santa Fe [written with James Hughes]
      - Shooting script, typescript, corrected (with notes), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 364)
    - Garden of Allah
      - "Breakdown from temporary script," mimeograph, 1936 Apr 1 (Box 22, Folder 365)
    - Love to Mamie
      - Synopsis, typescript, corrected (with notes), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 366)
    - Madame Curie
      - Synopsis, typescript carbon, 1937 Oct-Nov (Box 22, Folder 367)
      - Alternate story lines, typescript and carbon, 1937 Oct-Nov (Box 22, Folder 368)
    - The Plainsman
      - Shooting script, typescript carbon, 1950 Jun-Jul (Box 23, Folder 369)
    - Stand Up and Fight
      - Shooting script fragment, mimeograph, 1938 Aug 31 (Box 23, Folder 370)
    - The Vultures [written with Frank Conroy]
      - Synopsis, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 371)
  - SHORT STORIES
    - "Eben, the Hound and the Hare"
      See also: Journal, 1939-52, Box 8, folder 162
      - Draft 1, typescript, corrected, 1952 Jul 25 (Box 23, Folder 372)
      - Draft 2, typescript carbon, corrected, [1952] AUg 3 (Box 23, Folder 373)
      - Draft 3, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 374)
    - "Fabliau of Florida"
      - Typescript and carbon (Box 23, Folder 375)
    - "Rodent"
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 376)
  - SONGS
    - Ballads written by or copied by Lynn Riggs, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 377)
    - "Wranglin' That Steer," holograph, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 378)
  - SPEECHES
    - "Poetry --- and Poetry in the Theatre" A radio talk over WSUI, Iowa City, typescript, corrected, 1932 Nov 16 (Box 23, Folder 379)
    - Response to a citation award at the University of Oklahoma, typescript carbon, corrected (with an introduction by Dot Lemon), 1948 Apr 27 (Box 23, Folder 380)
    - "Some Notes on the Theatre" (Address to the San Diego Community Theatre), typescript, 1940 Feb 19 (Box 23, Folder 381)
      See also: Notes - Baylor University, Box 8, folder 167
    - "What the Theatre Can Mean to Us," (A speech to the Wednesday Luncheon Group, San Diego), typescript and carbon, corrected, 1940 Mar 26 (Box 23, Folder 382)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Alexander, Hi
      - "Shoo!," typescript carbon, ca. 1942 (Box 23, Folder 383)
    - Austin, Mary
      - "The Aged Poet Discourses," printed version, The Saturday Review of Literature, 1931 Aug 29 (Box 23, Folder 384)
    - Bynner, Witter
      - "Undergraduate," typescript (Box 23, Folder 385)
    - Clark, Barrett
      - "Lynn Riggs," [essay published in One-Act Plays, D. C. Heath & Company], typescript carbon, ca. 1930 (Box 23, Folder 386)
      - "An Open Letter to Mr. St. John Ervine," printed version, broadside, 1929 Mar 10 (Box 23, Folder 387)
    - Conkle, E. P.
      - "Death in Her Face," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 388)
    - Crews, Judson
      - "Psalms for a Late Season"
        See: Series I, Box 1, folder 1
    - Gelrud, Paul
      - Riel: Act 1, Scene 2 fragment photostat, ca. 1950 (Box 23, Folder 389)
    - Green, Paul
      - "The New Theatre," printed version, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 390)
    - H., H. W.
      - "The Keys to Heaven and Vice Versa," mimeograph (Box 23, Folder 391)
    - Hopkins, Gerard Manley
      - "A Nun Takes the Veil (Heaven-Haven)," typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 392)
    - Jilinsky, Andrius
      - "Address on Theatre," typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 393)
    - Johnson, Spud
      - "You Should Be Here (A Christmas Card)," printed version, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 394)
    - Kaho, Noel
      - "They Chew Tobaccer in Kansas," holograph, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 395)
    - Lesemann, Maurice
      - "All This for Spring," typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 396)
    - Locke, Sam
      - "Bringing Up Junior," typescript carbon, ca. 1942 (Box 23, Folder 397)
      - "Hollywood Premiere," typescript, ca. 1942
    - Long, Haniel
      See: Series I - Ann Webster, Box 6, folder 133
    - Lynch, Elizabeth Cook
      - "Sky Primitive," typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 398)
    - Meyer, Karl
      - "Sunrise" [screenplay], typescript carbon, bound, 1927
        See: Oversize, Box 32, folder 544
    - Naya, Ramon (Enrique Gasque-Molina)
      - "Cinquain 1," typescript, 1937 May 4 (Box 23, Folder 399)
      - "Empire in Durango"
        - Working notebook, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 400)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 401)
      - "A Letter from Spain"
        - Working notebook, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 402)
        - Draft 1, typescript, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 403)
        - Draft 1, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 404)
        - Draft 2, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 405)
      - "Mexican Mural"
        - Working notebook, 1938 Apr 3 (Box 24, Folder 406)
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 407)
        - Notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 408)
      - "A New World," typescript, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 409)
      - Poems, typescript carbon (with cover letter by Lynn Riggs), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 410)
    - O'Neil, George
      - "Adam's Wonder," typescript carbon (Box 24, Folder 411)
      - "Amulet," typescript (with note), n.d.
      - "Anachronistic Sonnet," typescript, n.d.
      - "Clarion," typescript carbon, n.d.
      - "Coincidence," holograph and typescript, 1928 Jan (Box 24, Folder 412)